DESMOND CHIN

FULLSTACK SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

INFO

ADDRESS

136, Everbright Jaya Off Kuching By Pass, Kuching, 93350, Malaysia

PHONE

+60165757252

EMAIL

contact@desmondchin.dev

LINKS

www.desmondchin.dev
github.com/desmondchoon

SKILLS

JavaScript

.

PHP

....

Java

 $\bullet \bullet \bullet \circ \circ$

Python

....

Databases

....

Linux Server

.

LANGUAGES

English

....

Bahasa Malaysia

 $\bullet \bullet \bullet \circ$

Chinese

....

PROFILE

Passionate fullstack developer who is experienced in delivering modern web and mobile applications using technologies such as ReactJS, NextJS, NodeJS, React Native, PHP, Java, and Python. Able to work on any part of the technology stack, with experiences in Linux Servers, SQL Databases, NoSQL Databases, and system administration. Interested in Research & Development, and latest technologies. Able to design, analyze, and develop systems or products from end to end.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Web Developer, Techninier Sdn. Bhd.

Kuching, Sarawak

Nov 2018 — Present

Partake in development, enhancement, and maintenance of company's products with latest web technologies. Responsible in handling company products from frontend to backend.

- Contributed and led the revamp of web applications to client-server architecture using ReactJS (NextJS) as frontend, and Laravel PHP Framework as backend.
- Handle systems integration with third party, for online payment, and telco subscription.

Software Developer, Sarawak Information Systems Sdn. Bhd. (SAINS)

Kuching, Sarawak

Feb 2016 — Oct 2018

Contributed in the development of building security based web applications, and also Java based asset management system using RFID technologies, mainly in library solutions.

- Partake in development, enhancement, and maintenance of company's software products.
- · Researched in Big Data, and Blockchain technologies.

INTERNSHIPS

R&D Trainee, Sarawak Information Systems Sdn. Bhd. (SAINS)

Jul 2014 — Jan 2015

Trainee in the Research and Development department. Assisted in research, product feasibility study, and testing.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Engineering (Electrical & Electronic Engineering), Swinburne University of Technology

Kuching, Sarawak

Kuching, Sarawak

Feb 2012 — Dec 2015

Honorary Secretary of IET Student Chapter and awarded the IET Leadership Award 2015. Researched in Image Processing, enhancing face detection algorithm.

St Joseph's School, Kuching

Kuching, Sarawak

Jan 2000 — Dec 2010

Proud prefect and Head of Multimedia of St Joseph's School Prefectorial Board 2009/2010. Vice Secretary of Interact Club.